#### **JOE MAINA KIMANI**

Tel: +254 705 777 588
Email: joemainak@gmail.com

#### **CAREER PROFILE SUMMARY**

I am a passionate IT enthusiast with an understanding of various elements of IT-related technologies and keen on growing as a professional. Through the course of my experience, my key skills in IT include but are not limited to; technical support, economics, network administration, network security, system administration, operating systems as well as troubleshooting and maintenance. Highlights of my experience include; installation of different operating systems on computers. (Windows and Linux Platforms), performing installation of required software as per the client's requirements, the configuration of networking devices, designing, implementing and commissioning of websites. I am flexible and can work in high-pressure environments and still deliver excellent results. Moreover, I also have excellent customer service skills. My goal is to develop my career in a company where my skills and experience will be utilized to contribute to the growth of the organization as an IT Officer.

#### **EDUCATION BACKGROUND**

- Masters of Science in Computer Systems Jomo Kenyatta University; 2021 Current (Coursework complete)
- Bachelor of Arts in Economics and Mathematics- Kenyatta University; 2012 to 2016.
- Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education- Kahuho Uhuru High School; 2008 to 2011.

#### **PROFESSIONAL COURSES**

- Cisco Certified Networking Professional: Core Networking I April, 2022
- Cisco Certified Networking Associate CCNA 200-301 January, 2022
- Python Basics Coursera; March, 2020
- Data Science Orientation Coursera; January, 2020.

#### **KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES ACQUIRED**

- **Object Oriented Programming:** Knowledge in OOP concepts using Java and Python with a keen understanding of abstraction, polymorphism, objects and classes and inheritance.
- **Systems Administration:** (LINUX & Windows Server) Skilled in the selection and disposal of redundant ICT equipment, performing regular data entry, data back-up and security checks with a keen understanding of SQL and data normalization techniques.
- Data Structures and Algorithms: Proficiency in Data Structures and Algorithms.
- IT Technical support: Experienced in monitoring and maintaining the computer systems and networks of an organization through installation and configuration of computer systems, diagnosing hardware and software faults and solving technical and applications problems.
- **Economics**: An expert in handling economic trend analysis, long-term macroeconomic projections, analysis of alternative trends and impact of fiscal and monetary measures and counterfactual simulations of the economy.
- **Mathematical skills**: Knowledge of Mathematical concepts, how to apply them properly and the various issues or problems that can arise when dealing with a mathematical operation.
- Network Administration: Knowledgeable in designing and deploying networks and performing network
  address assignment, scheduling maintenance of the LAN and wireless connectivity and actively involved in the
  configuration and troubleshooting process.
- **Virtualization and cloud computing:** Possesses expertise in virtualization and cloud computing with a concentration on infrastructure, software and platforms.
- Leadership skills: Greatly exploited leadership skills with the ability to provide leadership and strategic direction

- to the organization, ensuring that staff is all motivated towards effective service delivery and achieving the organization's greatest potential.
- **Troubleshooting and Maintenance:** Proficient at maintaining computer network infrastructure to ensure optimal uptime and best service and enforce an up-to-date systems backup.
- Website Development: Experienced in carrying out web development whereby I have been engaged in using tools such as JavaScript.
- **Network Security:** Ability to engage in any activity designed to protect the usability and integrity of your network and data by including both hardware and software technologies.
- Flexibility and Problem-Solving Abilities: Can work in a busy environment by maintaining calm under
  pressure and thinking through any possible threats that can occur in a system and plan for them before they
  happen.
- **Communication Skills:** Capability to relate well with employees and clients who need help with navigating their systems considering that every employee has their level of computer competency.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

## Independent IT Consultancy LogIT Systems; September 2020 to Date Duties and Responsibilities

- Installation of different operating systems to computers. (Windows and Linux Platforms)
- System analysis and UI design.
- LINUX and Windows Server administration.
- Microsoft Azure DevOps setup and configuration.
- Network design, installation and maintenance.
- SQL and NoSQL database troubleshooting and configuration.

# IT Consultant and End-User Support Passion for Nature / Credible Telekom (K), Zellyn Pest Control Experts; February 2012 to Date Duties and Responsibilities

- Ensuring output quality meets customer requirements by monitoring all devices and making required adjustments.
- Diagnosing and resolving incidents and requests from users.
- Installation, configuration and troubleshooting hardware and network equipment.
- Acquisition, installation and configuration of operating systems Windows and UNIX.
- Provision of training to users for products.
- Configuring system upgrades and setting access rights.

#### Website Design and Creation

### TCIM - Calgary, Money Objective, AMWG; August to December 2020 Duties and Responsibilities

#### Designing, implementing and commissioning the following websites;

- https://trumpetcallinternationalministries.org.
- https://moneyobjective.com.
- https://amomentwithgod.org.

# Team Leader/Technical Officer (IT) Team Tetea Kenya; August 2016 to August 2018 Duties and Responsibilities

- Spearheaded and led in team coordination.
- Logistics management for teams and briefed members on projects exhaustively.
- Sent out memos on projects.
- Installed different operating systems for computers (Windows and UNIX Platforms) and conducted hardware servicing.
- Escalation of application issues to relevant personnel.

• Replacement of products as required.

#### **OTHER PAST EXPERIENCES**

• Intern; Crystalyn Media, April to July 2016.

#### **OTHER ENGAGEMENTS**

- Voter Verification Clerk (VVC); Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission (IEBC), May to June 2017.
- Voter Registration Clerk (VRC); Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission (IEBC), January to February 2017.

#### **REFEREES**

#### Ibrahim Thuku

Director

Passion for Nature/Credible Telekom (K) Ltd

Mobile No.: +254 701 329 105 Email: <u>ibrahim.thuku@hotmail.com</u>

#### Samuel Mburu

Senior Project & Network Engineer

Dimension Data

Mobile No: +254 721 755 456 Email: s.mburu84@gmail.com

#### **A**nthony **N**guru

Founder

Team Tetea Kenya

Mobile No: +254 728 094 911 Email: antoinemuriithi@gmail.com

#### **Vincent Onyango**

Trumpet Call International Ministries – Canada

Mobile No.: +1 (403) 991-9371 Email: vinzonyango.vo@gmail.com